AHMED HUSSEIN

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

ABOUT ME

I am a passionate software engineer operating mainly with JavaScript, with 4+ years of experience constructing clean and quality products, building cross platform mobile applications using React Native and web applications using React.

I love implementing scalable, maintainable, testable, clean solutions - following established written procedures, guidelines, techniques, and best practices with a good eye for design and details.

WORK EXPERIENCE

REACT DEVELOPER @ YOURWELCOME

Feb 2021 - Present // Remote, UK

YourWelcome is the leading guest management & monetisation platform for alternative accommodation. Helping customers make more money from every booking.

Website: https://www.yourwelcome.com/ Website: https://www.propertycare.com/

Tech Stack: React, React Hooks, context API, GraphQL, Relay.

Key Responsibility: Building the new dashboard web application from scratch mentioned above.

REACT NATIVE DEVELOPER @ TARTEEL

Oct 2019 - Nov 2020 // Remote, USA

Tarteel is a US-based startup founded by passionate and innovative software engineers working in big tech companies, it is a Quran app that listens to your recitation and corrects mistakes using Al and ML.

Now it has 800+ App stores reviews and 100k users.

Website: https://www.tarteel.io/
iOS: https://bit.ly/2QSANc5

Tech Stack: React Native, React Hooks, context API, Redux ToolKit, socket.io, React Navigation, I18n, REST.

Key Responsibility: Building the mobile application from the ground up.

CONTACT

Website https://ahmed-hussein.com/
Phone 0020 110 294 9183
Email ahmedhussein.developer@gmail.com

GitHub /ahmedCodeGuy

LinkedIn /in/ahmed-hussein-developer

SKILLS

- HTML CSS JS (ES6) Typescript
- REACT REACT NATIVE REDUX
- GRAPHQL REST API Relay Apollo
- Jest Enzyme Storybook
- ENGLISH FLUENCY

EDUCATION

High Institute of Advanced Studies

2011 - 2015 // CAIRO, EG Bachelor of Management Information Systems

Harvard University

2013 - 2014 // Online, Edx.com CS50: Harvard's introduction to computer science.

Self-Study

2017 - 2018 // Online

I spent around a year of self-studying on many online platforms; the following is some of which.

Treehouse - Codecademy - Edx - Coursera - Udacity - Udemy - Egghead - Frontend

Masters - YouTube

REACT NATIVE DEVELOPER @ SNACKBOOK

May 2020 - Present // Remote, SA - Freelance

Basically it's Blinkist in Arabic.

Website: https://snackbook.me/ IOS: https://apple.co/2GSBkIR Android: https://bit.ly/2ZAHIeu

Tech Stack: React Native, Redux, Redux Thunk, React Navigation, I18n, react-native-track-player,

Firebase

Key Responsibilities: Adding new features to the mobile application, bug fixing, refactoring, and maintainging the existing code base.

REACT NATIVE DEVELOPER @ SAHL

Feb - May 2019 // Remote, SA - Freelance

Sahl is a Saudi company that is basically a software house.

I have been working on Faal it is an application for the **Saudi Arabia's Ministry of Education**, it helps to manage the communication process between schools and governmental educational departments.

Android: https://bit.ly/2xqUbpV

Tech Stack: React Native, Ignite, Redux, Redux Saga, React Native Navigation, I18next.

Key responsibility: Contributing on building the mobile application from scratch.

REACT NATIVE DEVELOPER @ SHOPZ

Jan 2018 - Feb 2019 // Maadi, EG

Shopz is a SaaS eCommerce mobile application, that integrates with existing eCommerce websites in a few clicks.

Website: https://shopz.io/
iOS: https://apple.co/33Q4sbb
Android: shorturl.at/FLNTU

Tech Stack:

Web: Material UI, React, Redux, Redux-Saga, React

Router, Parse.

Mobile: React Native, Expo, Storybook, React Navigation, GraphQL, Apollo, Formik.

Key responsibility: Contributing on a rebuild for the mobile application, maintaining and enhancing the current app and building the admins dashboard.